Preliminary Guide to the William Francis Whitmore Papers, 1945-1991
Department of Special Collections
Whitmore, William Francis. Papers,
1945-1991
M0915
Whitmore, William Francis.
36 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Mathematician in the field of oceanography; scientist and later consultant with Lockheed Missiles and Space Company. Head of the division of Thermal Energy Conversion where he worked on the development of the Polaris missile; later scientific analyst and consultant to various Department of Defense agencies.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Whitmore Family Trust, 1997.
Biography
Mathematician in the field of oceanography; scientist and later consultant with Lockheed Missiles and Space Company. Head of the division of Thermal Energy Conversion where he worked on the development of the Polaris missile; later scientific analyst and consultant to various Department of Defense agencies.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Lockheed Missiles and Space Company.; Naval Research Advisory Committee.; Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Program (National Science.; Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Conference.; Root, Leonard Eugene.; Oceanography.; Polaris missile.; Science--History.; Mathematicians--United States.
Collection Contents
- Biographical Material, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
- Chronological files1966, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
- Correspondence1966, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
- Naval Weapons Lab Dahlgren, 1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (correspondence, reports, reprint)
- Lockkheed Research Council, 1969-1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (correspondence, reports)
- Rand Corp., 1970, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
- Lockheed Research Council, 1966-1976, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (articles, correspondence)
- Meeting - House Committee on Science & Astronautics with Panel on Science & Technology, 1970, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (reprints, report)
- National Research Council, 1975-1977, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (correspondence, workshop schedule, articles, report)
- Workshop Materials, 1975, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (correspondence, articles, notes)
- Systems Analysis 1966-1967, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (reports, correspondence)
- NRAC (Naval Research Advisory Committee) Laboratory Advisory Board for Ordnance 1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (reports, correspondence, articles)
- LMSC (Lockheed Missile and Space Company) - Ocean Systems Consultants, 1961-1963, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (resumes, correspondence, requests)
- LMSC (Lockheed Missile and Space Company) - Ocean Systems Consultants,1963-1978, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
- DSB (Defense Science Board) Historical, 1961-1964, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
  (correspondence, articles)
- NRAC, 1977, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 1)
- WFW ChronJun 1968-Dec 1968, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- WFW ChronJan 1968-Jun 1968, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Chron - Whitmore 1967, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Correspondence - WFW 1967, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Travel Expenses, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- NAE (National Academy of Engineering) - Ocean Systems, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Lockheed Research Council, 1967, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Lockheed Research Council, 1968, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Lockheed Research Council, 1969, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- IAC (Industry Advisory Council), Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 2)
- Lockheed Research Council Minutes, 1964-1965, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Sea Bottom, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- OTEC (Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion), Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- OTEC - 1 Red Team, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Red Team, Sep 1977, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Fleet Ballistic Missile System, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Ocean Systems, 1968-1979, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- DSRV (Deep Submergence Rescue Vehicle) 1968, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Sherwin Speech Project, 1965-1966, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- DSB/IDA (Institute for Defense Analysis) Reviews, 1964-1966, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- FBM (Fleet Ballistic Missile System) 1976-1978, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Ocean Technology, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- Ocean Systems, 1980-1981, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- NRAC - NOL (Naval Ordnance Lab) - NWL (Naval Weapons Lab) - org. structures, 1968, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- NRAC, 1969-1973, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- NRAC, 1970-1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- NOL, 1973, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 3)
- NRAC, 1973, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- Lockheed Research Council, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- NRAC, 1968-1972, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- NRAC, 1971-1974, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
  (STRICOM Proposal)
- NRAC, Apr 1970-Sep 1970, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- NRAC, Sep 1969-Mar 1970, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- LABO (Laboratory Advisory Board for Ordnance), 1968-1969, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- NRAC Marine Corps Panel, 1970-1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- NRAC, 1969, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- Photographs, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- Notes on French Railroad System, 1945, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
- Logistics as a Target System, 1969, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 4)
  (article)
- Photographs, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- LMSC Nuclear, 1967, 1969, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- LMSC, Horizon, OceanSystems, FBM, 1971-1988, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
  (articles, photographs, correspondence, reports)
- C3 Contract, 1969-1987, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Personnel Records, 1959-1984, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1963, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- LABO, 1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- NAE - Marine Board, 1972-1975, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- WFW Miscellaneous Clippings, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- WFW Personal Letters, 1961-1967, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Articles, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Ocean Systems, 1973-1974, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Scaling Laws, 1970, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- NRAC, 1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- DSSV, 1968, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1971, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- Ocean Mining, 1974-1982, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- NAE Marine Board, Ocean Systems, 1974-1979, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 5)
- NAE Marine Board, Ocean Systems, 1974-1979, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Speeches, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Ocean Systems, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Ocean Systems, 1976-1977, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- NAE Meeting, Jun 1978, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Deep Sea Drilling, 1978, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Oil Spills, 1978, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Oil Recovery, 1976-1977, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Ocean Technology Transfer, 1973, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- Ocean Systems, 1977-1978, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- National Research Council - Marine Technology in the Federal Republic of Germany, 1977, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- "LMSC & Personal," 1959-1962, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
  (notes, articles, reports, correspondence, photographs)
- "LMSC & Personal," 1976-1991, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 6)
- "LMSC & Personal,"1964-1985, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 7)
  (notes, articles, correspondence)
- "LMSC & Personal,"1935-1972, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 7)
  (articles, correspondence, reprints, notes)
- "LMSC & Personal,"1964-1983, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 8)
  (reports, articles, clippings, correspondence, publications)
- "LMSC & Personal,"1979-1983, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 8)
  (articles, correspondence, newsletters, publications, brochures, reports, speeches)
- "LMSC & Personal,"1958-1967, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 8)
  (reports, articles, reprints)
- "LMSC & Personal,"1959-1973, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 9)
- Of Men and Stars, Lockheed history, Mar 1957-Jan 1958, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 9)
- Telephone Directories:, Accession no. 1997-018 (Box 9)
  Department of Energy, 1981 -- Office of Chief of Naval Operations, 1964 -- Special Projects, Dept. of Navy, 1965 -- LMSC, 1958-1982 (not complete) -- Daily Calendar Notes, 1979-1982
- Papers from master bedroom, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 1)
- Papers and reports, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 2)
- Papers and reports, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 3)
- Papers, NRAC & Personl, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 4)
- Documents/Miscellaneous, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 5)
- Papers, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 6)
- Documents/Miscellaneous, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 7)
- Papers, non-work, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 8)
- Lockheed papesr, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 9)
- Letters, R.S. Wersheim, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 10)
- Papers, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 11)
- Lockheed papers, personal file (w/vita), Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 12)
- Lockheed, activity logs, chief scientist 1962+, K.C. Black, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 13)
- Lockheed papers, Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 14)
- photos, prints, etc., Accession no. 1997-114 (Box 15)